Jim Sandoval

Software Engineer - Front-End

Alexandria, LA jsandoval.jim@gmail.com (435) 602-0046

Skillset

Vue.js, vuex, vue-router, Javascript, HTML. CSS, vuetify, bootstrap, webpack, node/npm, Jenkins, S3, Autho, Jest, Cypress, Git, Jira, Confluence, Java, MySQL, sockets, TIBCO, EC2, maven, Docker, Kubernetes, OpenShift

Passionate about software that delights users. Better yet: software that disappears as users effortlessly accomplish work.

I like apps that people use all-day, every-day to do complex work like trade securities or review genetic data in a clinical setting. I'm an expert with apps that coordinate multi-user workflows, often across companies, often significantly transform business processes. I like apps that are reliable and cheap to operate.

Broad and deep career as manager, full-stack developer, architect, consultant, co-founder. Long track-record of industry leading innovation. Excellent mentor. Team player.

Experience

2015 – Present - Dev Manager, Myriad Genetics. Managing 4 engineers writing tools to analyze and confirm genetic data for clinical oncology products. Responsible for all aspects of 20 separate applications, including 6 Java/Swing apps with complex data visualization and multi-user workflow. Responsible for Site Reliability Engineering for high-performance-compute environment. Led additional 2 engineers and 1 UX designer in design and build of modern front-end platform in Vue.js

2004-2015 - Principal Front-End Engineer, JPMorgan Chase. Product Owner, UX Designer, Front-End Engineer and Architect within mature, large-scale, high-performance microservice architecture. Designed and built eight separate advanced trading products for execution management platform, including innovative and industry-first Algorithm Management System allowing users to flowchart routing to different algos based on trade performance. 200,000 orders per day, 10,000 daily users, data centers in NA, EMEA and Asia, links to 150 exchanges, 500 exchanges and brokers, 10ms latency to exchanges. (Java, Swing, asynchronous messaging, FIX)

2003-2004 - TIBCO/EAI Consultant, Zettaworks

2001-2002 – CTO, Co-Founder, ForwardCast

1997-2001 - Architect/Full-stack Engineer, Bank of Boston

1994-1997 - Architect/Dev Manager, State Street Bank

1993-1994 – Lead Developer, University of New Mexico Hospital

1992 - Consultant, MORE, Inc

1987-1991 - Lead Developer, Citibank

1985-1986 - Analyst/Developer, BDM

Education

B.S., 1985, Applied Mathematics, University of New Mexico

Culture

Customer Obsession
Ownership
Invent and Simplify
Be Right, A Lot
Learn and Be Curious
Hire & Develop the Best
Insist on High Standards
Think Big
Bias for Action
Frugality
Earn Trust
Dive Deep
Backbone
Deliver Results